<!--
  @author Reika Kalseki
  
  Copyright 2018
  
  All rights reserved.
  Distribution of the software in any form is only allowed with
  explicit, prior permission from the owner.
-->
<?xml version="1.0"?>
<engines>
	<dc>
		<desc>
			The direct current (DC) engine is the simplest to make and operate. All it requires to function is a continuous redstone signal of any strength. This ease comes at a cost, though - these engines are the weakest of all, outputting %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ of torque at %d $SPEED_UNIT$ for %.3f$POWER_UNIT$ of power.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Redstone
			Requires Consumables: No
			Risks: None
		</note>
	</dc>
	<wind>
		<desc>
			The wind turbine uses wind to generate rotational power. Due to the low density of air, it does not generate much torque (only %d $TORQUE_UNIT$), but its design allows it to rotate at the rather rapid speed of %d $SPEED_UNIT$, producing a total of %.3f$POWER_UNIT$ at max efficiency. Note that the efficiency of this engine is only maximized when it is high up and out in the open. Objects and blocks can obstruct the blades of this engine.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Wind
			Requires Consumables: No
			Risks: Spinning Blades
			Notes: Requires free space in front of the turbine
		</note>
	</wind>
	<steam>
		<desc>
			The steam engine operates continuously if given a source of heat below it and water piped in. Slightly stronger than the previous engines, they provide %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ at %d $SPEED_UNIT$ (%.3f$POWER_UNIT$).
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Water and Heat
			Requires Consumables: Water
			Risks: Overheating at 150C
		</note>
	</steam>
	<gas>
		<desc>
			The gasoline engine, true to its name, runs on...ethanol. Simply load in ethanol crystals and watch them burn to produce %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ of torque at %d $SPEED_UNIT$, or %.3f$POWER_UNIT$ of power.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Ethanol
			Requires Consumables: Ethanol
			Risks: None
		</note>
	</gas>
	<ac>
		<desc>
			The alternating current (AC) engine, like its DC cousin, requires a redstone signal to perform. However, this one needs an alternating signal, best supplied with a redstone clock. Faster cycle times correlate to more consistent power output, with 2-clocks providing a constant supply of %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ at %d $SPEED_UNIT$ (%.3f$POWER_UNIT$). This engine requires a magnetized shaft core, which it will gradually de-magnetize.
		</desc>
		<note>
			<sub>
				<s1>
					Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
					Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
					Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
					Power Source: Redstone Clock and Magnetized Shaft Core
					Requires Consumables: Shaft Core Magnetization
					Risks: None
				</s1>
				<s2>
					Shaft cores can only be automatically extracted once fully demagnetized
				</s2>
			</sub>
		</note>
	</ac>
	<sport>
		<desc>
			The performance engine, like the gasoline engine, runs on ethanol, but it also requires water coolant and can only reach its maximum output when given the correct additives to its fuel supply - redstone, gunpowder, or blaze powder, each being more effective than the last. Fully supplied and maintained, these engines will produce %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ of torque at %d $SPEED_UNIT$, a total of %.3f$POWER_UNIT$.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Ethanol And Additives
			Requires Consumables: Ethanol and Redstone/Gunpowder/Blaze Powder
			Risks: Overheating at 240C
		</note>
	</sport>
	<hydro>
		<desc>
			The hydrokinetic engine converts the energy of falling liquids into shaft power. Note that this machine can only rotate countercloc$POWER_UNIT$ise, and therefore the waterfall must be positioned accordingly. Additionally, adjacent blocks can obstruct the paddles from rotating. Finally, this engine's power output is dependent on how far the water is falling. A 3-block fall will produce minimal power, but a 64+ block fall can produce %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ at %d $SPEED_UNIT$, the highest torque of any engine, totalling %.3f$POWER_UNIT$. These engines can also be chained, adding their torques together. This engine must be lubricated to function.
		</desc>
		<note>
			<sub>
				<s1>
					Max Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
					Max Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
					Max Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
					Power Source: Falling Liquids
					Requires Consumables: Lubricant
					Risks: Spinning Paddles
					Notes: Requires tall waterfalls to acheive full power
				</s1>
				<s2>
					At most 4 engines can be chained before the torque overloads the core shaft

					Can be upgraded with a bedrock shaft unit to increase that limit to 16 engines
					
					Liquid density and viscosity affect power production
				</s2>
			</sub>
		</note>
	</hydro>
	<micro>
		<desc>
			The microturbine is rather unique. When given a constant supply of fuel, it supplies very little torque (%d $TORQUE_UNIT$), but does it at an enormous speed of %d $SPEED_UNIT$, for a total output of just over two megawatts (%.3f$POWER_UNIT$).
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Jet Fuel
			Requires Consumables: Jet Fuel
			Risks: None
		</note>
	</micro>
	<jet>
		<desc>
			The most powerful engine of all, the gas turbine is a monster, outputting power comparable to that of an engine of a commerical jet airliner...and with sound to match. These engines will, when fuelled, provide %d $TORQUE_UNIT$ of torque at %d $SPEED_UNIT$ (%.3f$POWER_UNIT$). Be warned, unless you want to find out what it feels like to go through a blender, stay AWAY from the front of this one while in operation! Neither you nor your engine will fare well.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: %d $TORQUE_UNIT$
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: %.3f$POWER_UNIT$
			Power Source: Jet Fuel
			Requires Consumables: Jet Fuel
			Risks: Ingestion; Possible violent failure if damaged
		</note>
	</jet>
	<solar>
		<desc>
			The solar power plant is unique in that its size, and therefore its output, is scaleable. Simply build a tower of tower blocks, and surround the base with mirrors. More mirrors and taller towers mean more power. Note that the power comes out of the bottom of the tower, and water must be provided. Mirrors must be connected (possibly via other mirrors) to the tower to function.
		</desc>
		<note>
			Torque: Scaleable
			Speed: %d $SPEED_UNIT$
			Power: Scaleable
			Power Source: Sunlight
			Requires Consumables: Water
			Risks: Ignition of flammable blocks nearby
		</note>
	</solar>
</engines>
