<!--
  @author Reika Kalseki
  
  Copyright 2018
  
  All rights reserved.
  Distribution of the software in any form is only allowed with
  explicit, prior permission from the owner.
-->
<?xml version="1.0"?>
<resource>
	<steelingot>
		The steel ingot, made by smelting an iron ingot in a blast or pulse jet furnace, is the basis for all the machines, as only steel has sufficient tensile and shear strength to handle the loads applied by the machines.
	</steelingot>
	<othershaft>
		Shafts can also be crafted from wood, stone, diamond, or bedrock. Use a stick as the shaft part in a wood shaft. Bedrock varieties are crafting in the blast furnace like bedrock tools. Stronger materials allow for more torque to be transmitted at higher speeds. Overloading a shaft will cause it to violently fail.
	</othershaft>
	<othergearunit>
		Gear units can be made of the alternative gear types. Stronger gears wear down more slowly, and bedrock gears do not wear down at all. Simply craft them using the same base materials as a shaft, but subtituting a gear unit for the rod/shaft.
	</othergearunit>
	<othergear>
		Gears can be crafted from materials other than steel. Wood, Stone, Diamond, and Bedrock can also be used. Different materials consume lubricant and acquire damage at different rates. Bedrock gears do not require lubricant. Bedrock varieties are crafted in the blast furnace like bedrock tools.
	</othergear>
	<netherdust>
		Netherrack dust is made from grinding netherrack blocks in the grinder, while tar is made by grinding soul sand. Both of these are required constituents of jet fuel due to their hydrocarbon content.
	</netherdust>
	<sawdust>
		Make 20 stacks of wooden stairs? No problem; various wood items can be put in the grinder and ground into sawdust, which can be made back into wood or, to save sugarcane, into paper. Dye can be added to get alternate wood types.
	</sawdust>
	<beddust>
		Bedrock dust is produced when bedrock breakers completely grind away a bedrock block. This is an essential part of some machines, as bedrock is the only material hard enough to withstand the enormous pressures and temperatures. Additionally, it can be used to craft Bedrock Tools and Armor, and the best tier of shafts and gearboxes.
	</beddust>
	<extracts>
		Ore dust, slurry, and solution are intermediate products of the extractor. Slurry and solution require high input shaft speeds and a constant water supply, while the dust requires high input torque. None of these items has any other use.
	</extracts>
	<flakes>
		Ore flakes are the fourth stage output of the extractor. These can be smelted in an ordinary furnace to make ingots or gems of the source ore's material. Creation of this product requires high torque. Occasionally, the smelted product will need to be crafted into usable items of the target ore, such as with apatite, force, monazit/forcicium, and certus quartz.
	</flakes>
	<compacts>
		Anthracite, Prismane, and Lonsdaleite are intermediate stages of the coal compression process. Anthracite and Lonsdaleite can also be crafted into decorative blocks.
	</compacts>
	<decoblocks>
		Decorative blocks are made from 9 units of the respective materials, such as steel, anthracite, or lonsdaleite.
	</decoblocks>
	<glass>
		Blast Glass is made by smelting obsidian in a pulse jet furnace, and while transparent like glass, will resist nearly any explosion. Like ordinary glass, the blocks can also be crafted into blast glass panes.
	</glass>
	<spawners>
		If you are lucky enough to dig through a dungeon, mineshaft, or stronghold with a Boring machine or Pile Driver, the spawner, rather than being completely destroyed, will drop as a usable item, and will retain its mob type. This is an invaluable asset for mob farms, especially when combined with the spawner controller.
	</spawners>
	<yeast>
		Yeast is cultivated in the fermenter by adding sugar and water to dirt. It grows best at temperatures between 20 and 40 degrees, peaking at 25 degrees. Outside this range, it will grow slowly or not at all. Be careful - at temperatures above 60C, yeast will die. Ethanol sludge is made from adding yeast to plant matter and water. It is created most rapidly at around 35C.
	</yeast>
	<ethanol>
		Ethanol crystals are made from fermenting, then purifying in a centrifuge, then drying plant matter. These crystals can then be used as fuel in the ethanol and performance engines, as well as some other things.
	</ethanol>
	<bedingot>
		A bedrock ingot is used in the crafting of bedrock tools, armor, and some machines.
	</bedingot>
	<alloying>
		Some items and machines need special metal alloys, which are usually made in the Blast Furnace by adding the constituent ingredients into the main grid, and reaching the necessary temperature.
	</alloying>
	<silveringot>
		Silver ingots are used to make silver compounds. Silver is an occasional bonus from the extractor when processing gold.
	</silveringot>
	<salt>
		Salt is made from seawater, and is a source of iodine.
	</salt>
	<ammonium>
		Ammonium Nitrate is a useful ingredient in explosives such as the shells for the railgun.
	</ammonium>
	<silveriodide>
		Silver iodide is made from silver and iodine (from salt), and is used by the machine of the same name to induce rain.
	</silveriodide>
	<aluminum>
		Aluminum powder can be used with iron ingots to start a thermite reaction in the firestarter, providing more heat than any other fuel. It is an occasional bonus from the extractor when processing redstone. It can also be smelted into aluminum ingots.
	</aluminum>
	<railgunammo>
		Railgun ammunition is made from a ferromagnetic core and surrounded with heavy materials. Denser materials mean a more damaging impact. Each tier is crafted from adding mass to the previous one.
	</railgunammo>
	<slides>
		Projector Slides are inserted into the projector to display images. They can be crafted with dyes to create each other.
	</slides>
	<explosives>
		Explosive Shells are alternative ammunition for the railgun. They are cheaper to make, but deal less damage to entities hit by them, and are more destructive to the terrain around them.
	</explosives>
	<tungsten>
		Tungsten is a byproduct of processing iron ore in the Extractor, and is used for high-temperature, high-strength, or high-pressure applications. It can only be smelted in a vanilla furnace above %dC.
	</tungsten>
	<coke>
		Coal coke is a more efficient carbon source when making steel. Because of this, it can also be used as a furnace fuel, with a greater efficiency than pure coal.
	</coke>
	<name>
		
	</name>
	<name>
		
	</name>
	<name>
		
	</name>
	<name>
		
	</name>
	<name>
		
	</name>
	<name>
		
	</name>
</resource>
